<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>robert's blog</title>
  <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2016-11-13T23:53:46-08:00</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2014, Robert Benjamin</rights>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
  </author>
  
    <entry>
      <title>On Pseudo-Profound Bullshit</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/on-pseudo-profound-bullshit" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.sjdm.org/15/15923a/jdm15923a.pdf&quot;&gt;recently published study&lt;/a&gt; from the Journal of Judgment and Decision Making brought up a number of interesting points about the prevalence and level of acceptance of bullshit in society.
The paper’s worth checking out if you have the time, but if not, here’s some of my favorite bits, followed by a great summary by EvanRWT on Reddit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reddit-embed&quot; data-embed-media=&quot;www.redditmedia.com&quot; data-embed-parent=&quot;false&quot; data-embed-live=&quot;false&quot; data-embed-uuid=&quot;815d2daf-4a4a-4c44-b867-0f332a5af189&quot; data-embed-created=&quot;2016-11-14T07:38:55.936Z&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://np.reddit.com/r/news/comments/3v64hi/scientists_find_a_link_between_low_intelligence/cxkugrp/&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/a&gt; from discussion &lt;a href=&quot;https://np.reddit.com/r/news/comments/3v64hi/scientists_find_a_link_between_low_intelligence/&quot;&gt;Scientists find a link between low intelligence and acceptance of &amp;#x27;pseudo-profound bulls***&amp;#x27;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.redditstatic.com/comment-embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bullshit is a consequential aspect of the human condition. Indeed, with the rise of communication technology, people are likely encountering more bullshit in their everyday lives than ever before.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bullshit is not only common; it is popular…Using vagueness or ambiguity to mask a lack of meaningfulness is surely common in political rhetoric, marketing, and even academia. Indeed, as intimated by Frankfurt (2005), &lt;em&gt;bullshitting is something that we likely all engage in to some degree&lt;/em&gt;: ‘One of the most salient features of our culture is that there is so much bullshit. Everyone knows this. Each of us contributes his share.’ One benefit of gaining a better understanding of how we reject other’s bullshit is that it may teach us to be more cognizant of our own bullshit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That people vary in their receptivity toward bullshit is perhaps less surprising than the fact that psychological scientists have heretofore neglected this issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/on-pseudo-profound-bullshit</id>
      <updated>2015-12-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Boxes</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/boxes" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When you’re born, you’re placed into a number of boxes. You’re placed into a particular one if you’re male, a different one if you’re female: another dependent on whether your family is middle-class, poor, or rich. Another is decided by your parent’s beliefs, whether Christian, Atheist, Muslim, Buddhist, or other. You were born in the country side, or the city? Another box. In North America, or Europe, or Asia? Another box. In a loving family? With no family at all? Yet again, another box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your view of the world is restricted because you are in a box inside a box inside countless other boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is each box? An assumption. A list of conditions that hold true in your mind because you were told that they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boxes restrict the vantage point by which you view situations. Each box narrows the slit through which you see the world until the only light to reach your eyes is a pinpoint, a dot of reality backed by a wall of darkness.
Too many sit quietly, either sedated or unaware of the confined nature of their actuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what should you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be content. Don’t believe what you are told. If something doesn’t sit right with you, ask why, ask how, ask until your curiosity is fulfilled. Grab the indoctrinated version of success you were told would lead you to happiness and dissect it until you see what it truly is: a warped, one-size-fits-all, cookie cutter template that calls you a stick figure when you’re really a living, breathing, human being.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/boxes</id>
      <updated>2015-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Tony Hawk of Yesteryear</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/tony-hawk-of-yesteryear" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I’d imagine that right now, there’s someone out there that’s really, really good at say, skateboarding, and not good at much else. There’s some ridiculously skilled kid that thank god, got a crappy skateboard as a 8 year old and now is known globally for his or her skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But hold up&lt;/strong&gt; — skateboarding as we know it has only been around since the 40’s or 50’s, and the good skateboards used today have been available now only the last few decades!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would’ve happened if our prodigy skateboarding kid had been born a &lt;em&gt;hundred years ago&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many skills and talents are going to waste because the technology they rely on hasn’t been invented yet, or isn’t yet popular? How many god-like hover bike riders are there right now that think they aren’t good at anything? Or holo-pianists or multi-dimensional photographers or internal speech artists or AI therapists?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for that matter, how many skill-sets are antiquated and gone, skill-sets that certain people would have been extraordinary at? Why are people judged on how remarkable they are at whatever arbitrary talents exist and are viewed as desirable during their lifetime?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/tony-hawk-of-yesteryear</id>
      <updated>2015-08-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Wander in Porto</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/wander-in-porto" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/134719869&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t usually share videos here (in fact, I never have), but I was so impressed by this video I just had to. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/wander-in-porto</id>
      <updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>5 Months in San Sebastián</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/5-months-in-san-sebastian" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-08-16-5-months-in-san-sebastian/ocean.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s weird how distinctly I remember leaving. Saying goodbye to my family, boarding the plane, talking to the two college students sitting in front of me on the Trans-Atlantic flight. Forgetting to get a few Pounds for a coffee in Heathrow. I can recall it all perfectly, as if it was only a week ago. The experience we call “now” is so transient that sometimes the best moments refuse to become part of the past. And that’s what my time in San Sebastián was — possibly the most impactful five months of my life to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-08-16-5-months-in-san-sebastian/cityscape.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The cityscape in all it’s quiet glory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the April, one of my housemates made the observation that, even after all of us had returned from traveling Europe for two weeks, visiting Amsterdam, Berlin, Paris, Milan, Jerusalem, Budapest, and a host of other wonderful cities, San Sebastián was still our favorite: it was home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And indeed, Donostia isn’t a visiting city: it’s a living city. It’s a place where everything, from the style of grocery shopping to the beautiful parks to the quaint, impeccably decorated stores are all designed for you to slowly, deeply, and truly enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas the best moments in the big European cities all revolved around doing such and such or seeing this or that, my most treasured memories of San Sebastián were when we spent an hour at the beach, looking out over the waves and sipping Keler, or laughing with the owner of our favorite bar, Giroki, over the ‘plato del dia’ and a steaming hot cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/5-months-in-san-sebastian</id>
      <updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>On the Internet and the Printing Press</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/on-the-internet-and-the-printing-press" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What were the big jumps in methods of communication, or the transfer of knowledge? After a bit of thought, here’s what I’ve gotten:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speech.&lt;/strong&gt; Being able to speak (and creating languages that have become complex and intricate as they are now) was the first step. You could convey an almost unlimited number of desires, needs, and abstract ideas through speech.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing.&lt;/strong&gt; The development of written methods of communication provided a physical, more permanent method to convey ideas. They were more tangible and could last longer than they did in a person’s mind. They could remind a person of a thought they had previously forgotten about! And even crazier, you could read the text of someone you’ve never talked to, or someone dead! It was as if they could speak to you from the grave.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Printing Press.&lt;/strong&gt; While the printing press isn’t the first machine for reproducing written texts, it was certainly the first wildly successful one. Now, not only could ideas last years, but they could reach masses of people! Thousands of people could read the same words and be exposed to the ideas of one writer!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Internet.&lt;/strong&gt; And finally, where we are now. The internet is what I believe to be the final step before humans ascend to some kind of superorganism. With the advent of the internet, not only could text be transferred on a global level nigh instantly, but also real-time discussion, digital images, video, code, applications, sound (music!!), and a myriad of other stunning forms of content, many of which didn’t even exist ten or fifteen years ago. This is stunning. Seriously, it’s completely beyond belief. Forget predictions of flying cars or even flying cities, you can write a dumb little sentence on your smartphone, post it on Twitter, and instantly, anyone in the world can read it. That is a god-like power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above thoughts came when I tried to deconstruct my interest in web development. I never really liked the idea of engineering/coding, probably because it seemed too technical/mathematic and didn’t at all appeal to my visual/creative/artistic side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why have I picked up a interest in web development over the last year or so? Because, in the context of the above, web development is the equivalent of working at a hot, bustling printing press with Johannes Gutenberg himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You stand side by side a crowd of other people creating not only “book covers” (standard websites, blogs), but also a number of other things that are only limited by your creativity! Physical books aren’t interactive: they can speak to you deeply and truly, but you can’t talk back to it. It’s a one-way transfer of information (which is certainly valuable!). Web development allows things like interaction to content. It allows you to converse with other people, swapping crazy theories or ideas (like this little blurb) and revel in each other’s madness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember reading through Bill Bryson’s “A Short History of Nearly Everything,” and griping that I hadn’t been born into a wealthy English family in the 1750s. Then, I thought, I truly would’ve fit in. A man could learn the basics of science and philosophy and math and, with a little creativity, immediately begin working on problems no one had thought of before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an exciting time filled with discoveries and true intellectual exploration. Bones were unearthed and ruminated over, moralities were questioned, and lofty physics theorems were tossed about like a baseball. I felt that, nowadays, everything worth saying had already been said and the only truly exciting developments were in the hands of incredibly niche, PHD level researchers who had spent a decade and a half in higher education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I failed to realize, overlooking my delusions of the 1750’s being a fairyland, was that this exciting exploration and creating environment still exists, in the internet. And while you certainly can join or utilize the power of the internet with almost any skill set, whether writing, marketing, music, or photography, learning web development opens up a whole new world of possibilities that can be combined with those skills with amazing results.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/on-the-internet-and-the-printing-press</id>
      <updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>No, That's Not the 'Future of the Web'</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/no-thats-not-the-future-of-the-web" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I keep seeing all these articles stating “_ is the best!”
“Start making _, it will be all there is in a year!” and so on and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particular one that triggered me to write this is a particular article going on about &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.intercom.io/why-cards-are-the-future-of-the-web/&quot;&gt;why cards are the “future of the web”&lt;/a&gt;. The actual article is quite well written — what bugs me is the phrase “future of the web.” You could point out that I’m arguing semantics, and that’s certainly true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the point remains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The only certain thing about the future is that it will be a time of more uncertainty than ever before, whether economically, culturally, politically, or especially technologically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one could’ve accurately predicted the shift to flat design and minimalism, or the obsession with parallax scrolling. Web or technological trends are just that, trends. Trends come and go, rise in popularity and fall in popularity, and in the upcoming years the rapidity with which they will evolve will only continue to accelerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see or predict a trend, that’s fine! You might be right on! But don’t say it’s “the future” if it’s something as temporary and short-termed as cards. The future of the web might be VR websites, or direct neural connectivity. It might be some bizarre form of physical manifestation or integrated reality. But cards are no more the future of the web than the design patterns of Web 2.0 were. They’ll be here for a year and gone the next.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/no-thats-not-the-future-of-the-web</id>
      <updated>2015-04-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Internal Dialogue and Learning Styles</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/internal-dialogue-and-learning-styles" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-04-04-internal-dialogue-and-learning-styles/tree.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dictation-of-ideas-pt-1&quot;&gt;Dictation of Ideas Pt. 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly strange and impromptu experiment on dictating and recording thoughts and writing them down later. Picture this: I’m just walking along minding my own business when a novel new idea pops into my head. I proceed to follow the initial idea down a massive train of thought, jumping from one idea to the next, and making fascinating connections, but by the time I get back to somewhere where I have paper or a computer, the entire chain of thought is just gone, and I don’t remember it! I’ve lost a lot of good ideas from this happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, talking in my head or out loud is a very natural, streamlined process. When the interesting idea appears in my head, it flits around for a bit, then soon begins to take on a life of its own. Whether I speak aloud (to myself) or keep it as internal dialogue, I begin to go on a mental rampage, chaining one concept to the next, looping in circles, and generally taking a wild, maniacal trek through vaguely connected subjects, arts, or emotions. It takes a lot of effort for me to be able to spew my various brain farts directly into writing. It’s happened before, certainly, but not that often and never when I intend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous information is necessary as background to &lt;em&gt;why I prefer to learn by reading rather than by watching or hearing.&lt;/em&gt; In the past, I’ve almost exclusively learnt by reading, although recently I discovered a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7U81PaxuxNA&quot;&gt;insightful&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pVbLlnmxIbY&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; and interviews of people like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NU7W7qe2R0A&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eqtuNXWT0mo&quot;&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91ytSdSM-Kk&quot;&gt;David Foster Wallace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The reason why I typically prefer reading over videos or podcasts is because you can choose how quickly you’re processing the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a video or podcast, there are ways to speed up or slow down the content — but it’s a constant. If you speed up an audio file or video to play 1.5x faster, it’s always that much faster, and it’s never variable unless you continually fiddle with it. &lt;strong&gt;It doesn’t actively change depending on the content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m reading, I have the ability to read very quickly if the text makes intuitive sense to me, and slow down if it’s more complicated, or if a related idea appears in my head. If there’s a section I don’t understand, I can immediately stop and reread as necessary until the point the author is making is drilled into my head.
It’s kind of funny the way it works — ideas seem to come out of my head in a torrential outpour when I speak or think, but when I’m learning something, it doesn’t work the same way. Your mouth obviously isn’t an input (you don’t hear things from your mouth), but you’d assume that if you could rapidly speak things and understand them well, the opposite would also work in that you could hear things quickly and comprehend them — but it doesn’t work that way at all. I understand things when I read them, and I create things when I speak them or think them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entire blurb is a tangentially related, overly complex way of saying that learning styles matter, a lot. But if the elaborate &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning_styles&quot;&gt;Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt; is any indication, nobody entirely understands how they work, and certainly not their relationship to creative work and value creation. Taking the time to observe how you best learn things is an important first step to 1) learning faster and better and 2) working on learning in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/internal-dialogue-and-learning-styles</id>
      <updated>2015-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>The Golden Hour</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/the-golden-hour" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/195330662&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=true&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In photography, there’s a term called the golden hour right before the Sun sets or rises. During this time, the sky turns a soft, glowing hue of red and pink and the world briefly becomes a bit more beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures of this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-03-19-the-golden-hour/pier.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Looking out towards the pier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-03-19-the-golden-hour/kayaking.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A couple of locals kayaking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-03-19-the-golden-hour/handprint.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A handprint on the marbled stone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-03-19-the-golden-hour/stones.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The sturdy stone blocks divides the ocean from the pier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-03-19-the-golden-hour/water.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A beautiful shade of light orange cast on the swirling waters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-03-19-the-golden-hour/city.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Looking back towards the city.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/the-golden-hour</id>
      <updated>2015-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>The Internet's Effect on My Attention</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/the-internets-effect-on-my-attention" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The arrival of the internet means that, for possibly the first time in human history, knowledge is in overabundance for the average person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is far, far more good, quality content being produced that one could physically or mentally consume in their lifetime, even if that was their sole purpose in life. &lt;strong&gt;As knowledge-seeking individuals, this is problematic.&lt;/strong&gt; What happens when you take a starved man and sit him down in front of a feast? He gorges himself to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet’s effect on my attention is alarming. When browsing the internet, I will visit sites with vast amounts of interesting content on them: I will open up 5 or 10 or 20 tabs of things I want to view, then manically switch between them, reading a snippet of this or watching a bit of a video. Many of these pieces of content lead to me opening another several tabs, and the cycle continues. It’s attempting to satiate a unsatisfiable desire for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This behavior has bled over to my reading habits: I’ll be reading a fantastic book on my iPad, get bored after a few pages, then switch to another book. Then another. I have access to hundreds of books right at my fingertips, so instead of treasuring one or two at a time I’ll attempt to switch off between all of them in a hopeless undertaking to have it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In doing this, I fail to realize that, in this day and age, sanity doesn’t come from choosing what you consume, it comes from choosing what you &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, for the first time, I’ve decided to control what I read, watch, and listen to. Delete all your tabs, Robert. Open one website, enjoy what you read, then close it. No more of this endless feast, you have no time to be full if all you do is eat.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/the-internets-effect-on-my-attention</id>
      <updated>2015-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Music Compilation: Part 2</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/music-compilation-part-2" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick post: found this weird, delightful Russian electronic album on &lt;a href=&quot;http://hypem.com/&quot;&gt;Hype Machine&lt;/a&gt; just now, loving it so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;yes&quot; src=&quot;http://hypem.com/premiere-embed/sbpch&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height:600px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/music-compilation-part-2</id>
      <updated>2015-02-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Music Compilation: Part 1</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/music-compilation-part-1" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/At1vTJI8lj0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those rare songs that doesn’t particularly stand out at first, but then grabs you by the collar in a single smooth, slow motion and demands your ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/189815210&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=true&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/185229711&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=true&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one has a particular night-cruise feel about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/143729872&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=true&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/music-compilation-part-1</id>
      <updated>2015-02-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>San Sebastián: First Impressions</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/san-sebastian-first-impressions" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-01-26-san-sebastian-first-impressions/san-sebastian.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To understand the world at all, sometimes you could only focus on a tiny bit of it, look very hard at what was close to hand and make it stand in for the whole. — Donna Tart, The Goldfinch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-01-26-san-sebastian-first-impressions/mossy-stones.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mossy stones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-hike&quot;&gt;The Hike&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my housemates and another friend of ours decided to take a spontaneous hike up the mountains past the far east side of Zurriola beach — we didn’t really have a plan, but just started walking towards the mountain and took whichever path looked steeper!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-01-26-san-sebastian-first-impressions/pony.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A pony at a small farm on the east side of the coastline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exploring-the-coastline&quot;&gt;Exploring the coastline&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The path we took lead us through a few neighborhoods to some less-trodden stone paths, and eventually to the actual hiking trails atop the mountain. These pictures don’t do justice. Imagine Studio Ghibli in reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-01-26-san-sebastian-first-impressions/castle.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;At the bottom of the peninsula were the ruins of a ~1700s era castle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-01-26-san-sebastian-first-impressions/seagulls.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Seagulls crowding by the shoreline penisula.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/san-sebastian-first-impressions</id>
      <updated>2015-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>An Introduction</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/an-introduction" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2015-01-26-an-introduction/tableboards.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to create a blog of some kind for awhile, but ended up putting it off until now. I didn’t want to create one entirely from scratch, but wanted to be involved enough in the process that I learned a lot more about basic web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-goals&quot;&gt;The Goals:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;post-regularly&quot;&gt;Post regularly:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole blog will be pointless if I don’t take the time to post stuff on it. I need to keep it in mind as I’m dealing with my daily workflow and travel, and update every couple weeks at a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;practice-writing&quot;&gt;Practice writing:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to work on writing. I have a lot of whimsical interests that I flirt with, and certainly all of them have intrinsic value, but writing is the one that’s been on my mind the most and the one I’ve acted on the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web development, music production, photography, and online marketing are great, but writing seems closer to my heart than any of those. I’ve been reading virtual stacks of good novels on my iPad and absurd numbers of articles online, and it almost feels wrong to take in such quality without outputting any writing. It’s like mental constipation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;learn-development&quot;&gt;Learn development:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What little I’ve done has been pretty difficult, admittedly! Getting changes to properly push from my local server and the linux server is way more of a pain that it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/an-introduction</id>
      <updated>2015-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Robert Benjamin</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
